<?xml version="1.0"?>
<document>
  <properties>
    <title>Changes</title>
  </properties>

  <body>
	<release version="0.9.3" date="in CVS">
      <action dev="vanto" type="add">
		Software Evolution Matrix Chart has been added. It shows up the file 
		size evolution between tagged versions.
      </action>
	</release>
	<release version="0.9.2" date="2004-03-16">
      <action dev="vanto" type="update">
		BR tags have been replaced by DIV tags to work around weird
		jelly behaviour that inserts whitespaces between an opening
		and closing BR tag causing most browsers to print an
		additional line break.
      </action>
      <action dev="vanto" type="fix">
		All commit comments are wrapped in a CDATA element now to fix
		#1480.
      </action>
      <action dev="vanto" type="add">
		A new report with a list of the most common commit comments
		has been added.
      </action>
      <action dev="vanto" type="update">
		The misleading error message about a missing picture has been
		rephrased. 
      </action>
      <action dev="squig" type="fix">
		The handling of empty section names in the html output has
		been fixed. Empty sections headers are now omitted.
      </action>
      <action dev="vanto" type="fix">
		Exception in AuthorOfTheMonthReport has been fixed.
		Now the author with the most new lines in this month scores.
      </action>
    </release>
	<release version="0.9.1" date="2004-03-07">
      <action dev="squig" type="add">
		Complete customizability of the generated documents through an
		XML file has been implemented.
      </action>
      <action dev="squig" type="add">
		Grouping has been added to support easy parameterization of
		charts.
      </action>
      <action dev="squig" type="add">
		Scritability using Jexl to filter input and output values has
		been added.
      </action>
      <action dev="vanto" type="add">
		The commit activity chart from StatCvs has been merged.
      </action>
      <action dev="vanto" type="add">
		A document with recent activity has been added.
      </action>
      <action dev="vanto" type="add">
		A report that list the author with the highest lines of code
		delta per month has been added. 
      </action>
      <action dev="vanto" type="update">
		The author page now support a picture of the author to be
		displayed. 
      </action>
      <action dev="squig" type="update">
		History feature has been rewritten. Instead of calling cvs
		from StatCvs-XML it is required to check out all 1.1 revisions
		to a working directory prior to running StatCvs-XML.
      </action>
      <action dev="squig" type="update">
		The documentation has been updated.
      </action>
      <action dev="squig" type="update">
		The updated cvs log parsing code has been merged from
		StatCvs. This includes fixes for partial logs and for handling
		of logs generated by cvsnt.
      </action>
      <action dev="squig" type="update">
		Simplyfied stylesheet to support custom reports.
      </action>
      <action dev="squig" type="fix">
		Version output has been fixed.
      </action>
      <action dev="squig" type="fix">
		The headless property is now set to make JFreeChart work on
		machines without a graphical display.
      </action>
    </release>
	<release version="0.9.0" date="2003-09-17">
      <action dev="vanto" type="add">
		First release based on StatCvs 0.13.
      </action>
    </release>
  </body>
</document>
