<?xml version="1.0"?>

<document>

<properties>
 <title>Concepts</title>
</properties>

<body>

  <section name="Introduction">

  <p>The following sections describe concepts used by StatCvs-XML to
  generate reports.</p>

  </section>

  <section name="Domain">

  <p>
    Each report works on a specific set of data called the domain. The
    following domains are available in StatCvs-XML:

    <ul>
      <li>Files</li>
      <li>Directories</li>
      <li>Revisions</li>
    </ul>

    That means a report can either work an a list of files,
    directories or revisions, i.e. the LocChart works on revisions,
    adding up all line deltas.
  </p>

  </section>

  <section name="View">

  <p>
    The default domain is the global data object that contains all
    files, directories and revisions. Sometimes it is desirable to
    select a subset of that data though. This could be done with a
    filter matching only the relevant item of course. That would be a
    rather tedious solution though in case it was desired to generate
    a specific set of records for each author for
    instance.
  </p>

  <p>
    StatCvs-XML has a concept called view for that purpose. A view can
    be specified in a document tag by setting the attribute
    <tt>foreach</tt> to one of the following values:

    <tt>
    <ul>
      <li>author</li>
      <li>directory</li>
      <li>file</li>
      <li>module</li>
      <li>symbolic name (cvs tag)</li>
    </ul>
    </tt>
  </p>

  <p>
    If no <tt>foreach</tt> attribute is set, the document will be
    generated using the global domain. 
  </p>

  <p>
    Not every view can provide every domain. You need to make sure
    that the domain of all reports in the document is matched. 

    <table>
    <tr>
      <th>View</th>
      <th>Supported Domains</th>
    </tr>
    <tr>
      <td>Global</td>
      <td>
        All
      </td>
    </tr>
    <tr>
      <td>Author</td>
      <td>
        <ul>
          <li>Revisions</li>
        </ul>
      </td>
    </tr>
    <tr>
      <td>Directory</td>
      <td>
        <ul>
          <li>Directories (Recursively All Subdirectories)</li>
          <li>Files</li>
          <li>Revisions</li>
        </ul>
      </td>
    </tr>
    <tr>
      <td>Module</td>
      <td>
        <ul>
          <li>Files</li>
          <li>Revisions</li>
        </ul>
      </td>
    </tr>
    </table>
  </p>

  <p>
    <img src="images/views-simple.png"/>
  </p>

  </section>  

  <section name="Grouping">

  <p>
    Most reports compare data that is grouped by some criteria. For
    instance the AuthorsLocChart groups all revisions by author and
    draws a time line per author. Most StatCvs-XML reports can be
    customized to group by other than the default criteria by
    setting <tt>groupby</tt> to one of the following values:

    <ul>
      <li>author</li>
      <li>file</li>
      <li>directory</li>
      <li>module</li>
      <li>symbolicName</li>
    </ul>
  </p>

  <p>
    Which values apply depends on the domain of the report:
  
    <table>
    <tr>
      <th>Domain</th>
      <th>groupby</th>
    </tr>
    <tr>
      <td>Directories</td>
      <td>
        None
      </td>
    </tr>
    <tr>
      <td>File</td>
      <td>
        <tt>
        <ul>
          <li>directory</li>
          <li>module</li>
        </ul>
        </tt>
      </td>
    </tr>
    <tr>
      <td>Revisions</td>
      <td>
        All
      </td>
    </tr>
    </table>
  </p>

  <p>
    Revisions are the atomic unit of the data model. Therefore reports
    that work on revisions, as most reports do, offer the most
    flexible grouping abilities.
  </p>

  </section>

</body>

</document>
  