<?xml version="1.0"?>

  <document>

	<properties>
	  <title>Manual</title>
	</properties>

	<body>

	  <section name="Introduction">

        <p>This is the StatCvs-XML manual. Please see the <a
        href="http://statcvs-xml.berlios.de/">StatCvs-XML</a> pages
        for a general introduction to the program.</p>

        <p>This manual is based on the <a
        href="http://statcvs.sf.net/manual/">StatCvs Manual</a>.</p>

	  </section>

	  <section name="Prerequisites">

		<p>To run StatCvs-XML you need:

          <ul>
            <li>
              <b>Java version 1.4</b> or above. Type <tt>java
              -version</tt> on the command line to see your Java
              version. See the <a href="http://java.sun.com/">Java</a>
              pages for a recent Java Runtime Environment (JRE).
            </li>
            <li>
              <b>The CVS client</b> for creating CVS logfiles. Both <a
              href="http://www.cvshome.org/">CVS</a> (for Unix) and <a
              href="http://www.cvsnt.org/">CVSNT</a> (for Windows) are
              supported.
            </li>
          </ul>
		</p>

	  </section>

	  <section name="Quickstart">

		<p>
          It takes three steps to create reports for a CVS module:

          <ol>
            <li>Check out a copy of the module from CVS</li>
            <li>Create a CVS log for the module</li>
            <li>Run StatCvs-XML</li>
          </ol>         
        </p>

        <subsection name="Checking out a module from CVS">

          <p>
            You can skip this step if you have already checked out a
            working copy. Typically, the command looks somewhat like
            this (replace <tt>[cvsroot]</tt> and <tt>[module]</tt> 
            with the cvs module and root you want to check out):
          </p>

          <p>
            <tt>cvs -d[cvsroot] checkout [module]</tt>
          </p>

        </subsection>

        <subsection name="Creating a CVS log file">
 
          <p>
            Change into the directory where you have checked out the
            module, and use the <tt>cvs log</tt> command to create a
            log file.
          </p>

          <p>
            <tt>cvs log &gt; cvs.log</tt>
          </p>

        </subsection>

        <subsection name="Running StatCvs-XML">

          <p>
            StatCvs is run using the command:
          </p>

          <p><tt>java -jar statcvs-xml-full.jar</tt></p>

          <p>
            This will generate the reports in the html documents in a
            directory <tt>statcvs-xml-out/</tt>. The directory
            will be created if it does not exist, yet. Point your
            browser to <tt>statcvs-xml-out/index.html</tt> to access
            the table of contents of the generated reports.
          </p>

        </subsection>

	  </section>
	  
	  <section name="Command Line Options">

        <p>
          StatCvs-XML can be configured through a file named <a
          href="settings.html"><tt>statcvs.xml</tt></a> that needs to
          located in the directory where StatCVS-XML is started or
          through the command line. The command line options overwrite
          the settings made in <tt>statcvs.xml</tt>. Run StatCvs-XML
          like this:
        </p>

        <p>
          <tt>java -jar statcvs.jar [options] [logfile
          [working-directory]]</tt>
        </p>

        <p>
          See below for a list of the most important command line
          options. Run StatCvs-XML with the <tt>-help</tt> options to
          see a list of all options.
        </p>
        
        <p>
          <dl>
            <dt><tt>-output-dir directory</tt></dt>
            <dd>
              Specify an output directory. The reports will be
              generated in this directory. The directory will be
              created if it does not exist.
            </dd>

           <dt>
             <a name="filters"/>
             <tt>-include include-pattern-list</tt><br/>
             <tt>-exclude exclude-pattern-list</tt>
           </dt>
           <dd>
             <p>
               Specify filters to exclude files from the analysis. A
               file will be ignored if it doesn't match any of the
               patterns in <tt>include-pattern-list</tt>, or if it
               matches any pattern in
               <tt>exclude-pattern-list</tt>.
             </p> 

             <p>
               The patterns are lists of <a
               href="http://ant.apache.org/">Apache Ant</a>-style
               wildcard patterns, seperated by colons or
               semicolons. The wildcards are:
             </p>

             <p>
               <ul>
                 <li>'?' matches a single character</li>
                 <li>'*' matches zero or more characters</li>
                 <li>'**' matches zero or more directories</li>
               </ul>
             </p>

             <p>For example, <tt>src/**/*.java</tt> matches all java
             files in the <tt>src</tt> directory or its
             subdirectories. Note that <tt>*.java</tt> only matches
             java files in the root directory, because '*' does not
             match subdirectories.</p>

             <p>One more example:</p>

             <p><tt>-include **/*.c;**/*.h -exclude legacy/**</tt></p>

             <p>This matches all <tt>.c</tt> and <tt>.h</tt> files
             anywhere in the directory tree except those in the
             <tt>legacy</tt> directory and its subdirectories.</p>

             <p>For more information on Ant's wildcard syntax, see the
             <a
             href="http://ant.apache.org/manual/dirtasks.html#patternset">Patternset
             section of the Ant manual</a>.</p>

             <p>If not specified, all files will be included and no
             files will be excluded.</p>
           </dd>

           <dt><tt>-title title</tt></dt>
           <dd>
             <p>Specifies a display title to be used in the
             reports. The name of the CVS module will be used as
             default if no title is specified.</p>
           </dd>

           <dt><tt>-weburl url</tt></dt>
           <dd>
             <p>Specify the URL of a web repository like ViewCvs,
             WebCvs or Chora. This must be the URL of the page for the
             module's root directory. StatCvs will create links to
             ViewCVS for directories, files and revisions.</p>
           </dd>

           <dt><tt>-renderer renderer</tt></dt>
           <dd>
             <p>Specify the document renderer. Useful values include
             html, xdoc and xml. You can also specifiy a full
             qualified name of a Java class, that is available in the
             classpath.</p>
           </dd>

           <dt><tt>-document-suite &lt;filename&gt;</tt></dt>
           <dd>
             <p>Specify the document suite. The default is
             <tt>resources/suite.xml</tt>.</p>
           </dd>
          </dl>
        </p>

      </section>

	<section name="History">
	  <p>When directories are deleted from cvs and the working copy is
		updated using the prune flag, these directories are not
		included in the cvs log anymore. If StatCvs-XML is run on such
		a log, the total lines of code are still correct but the lines
		of code progression in the charts may not be.</p>
	  
	  <subsection name="Analysing the complete history">
		<p>If you would like to analyse the complete project history,
		  you need to specify that the first revision of each file
		  should be checked out:</p>

		<p><tt>cvs -d[cvsroot] -r1.1 checkout [module]</tt></p>

		<p>Then change to the created directory and create the cvs log
		  as usual:</p>

		<p><tt>cvs log &gt; cvs.log</tt></p>
	  </subsection>
	</section>

	</body>
  </document>
  